Guide to the Wesley Clair Mitchell Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: [C] Correspondence, (8 Boxes: Boxes 7-14)
  - Loomis, Roger S.
    - 1923 Feb 26; carbon 1 p; copy 1 p; WCM reply to 2/23; grants permission (Box 11)
  - Lotka, Alfred J.
    - 1947 Nov [?J; t.l.s. 1 p; address notification (Box 11)
  - Loveman, Amy
    - 1948 Jul 13; t.l.s. 1 p; requests WCJ1 review J. Goodbar and L. Bergeron’s A Creative Capitalism for Saturday Review of Literature (Box 11)
  - Lowe, Adolphe
    - 1937 Apr 12; a.l.s. 1 p; meeting plans (Box 11)
  - Lowell, A. Lawrence
    - 1909 Aug 12; telegram; Harvard appointment offer (Box 11)
    - 1909 Aug 12; t.l.s. 2 p; Harvard offer; earlier School of Business offer (Box 11)
    - 1910 Jan 14; t.l.s. 1 p; renews Harvard offer (Box 11)
  - [Lynd, Robert S.] (signed R.S.L.)
    - 1)
      - 1929 Feb 9; t.l. 1 p; urges WCM to permit Rice to use letter to J.M. Clark (Box 11)
  - Lynd, Robert S.
    - 1)
      - 1937 Feb 6; a.l.s. 1 p; asks WCM become sponsor Columbia University Faculty Committee to Aid the Spanish People; letter to public on Committee encl. (l p) (Box 11)
      - 1937 Feb 9; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 2/6; assents (Box 11)
    - 2)
      - 1939 Apr 22; t.l.s. 1 p; declines invitation to WCM’s address on Knowledge for What?; on WCM, Veblen, Dewey, L. Frank (Box 11)
      - 1939 Apr 24; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 4/22; Plan of treatment in address (Box 11)
      - 1939 May 3; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; sends NB annual report - NB method of choosing topics of :study (Box 11)
      - [1939], May 8; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 5/3; NB topic choice; WCM and Mills influence in economics (Box 11)
      - 1939 May 9; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 5/8 (Box 11)
    - 3)
      - [1941]Dec 22; t.l.s. 3 p; on revision WCM "National Unity and Intellectual Freedom" (Box 11)
      - 1944 May 30; a.l.s. 2 p; copy 1 p; on WCM retirement, WCM as theorist and empiricist, Dewey, Veblen (Box 11)
      - 1944 May 31; carbon 2 p; copy 2 p; WCM reply to 5/30; self and development of social sciences (Box 11)
      - 1947 Nov 10; a.l.s. 1 p; WCM health (Box 11)
      - [n.d.]; a.l.s. 1 p; wants WCM to join committee; G. Counts (Box 11)
  - Macauley, Frederick R.
    - 1937 Apr 19; copy of telegram; WCM telegram; meeting plans (Box 11)
  - Macdougall, William
    - [1910 ?] May 2; a.l.s. 2 p; thanks for copy article ["Rationality of Economic Activity"] (Box 11)
  - MacIver, Robert M.
    - 1937 Apr 28; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for copy BASM; sends copy own Society (Box 11)
    - 1937 Apr 30; carbon 1 p; WCM reply 4/28; thanks copy Society; on sociology - A. Small (Box 11)
    - 1937 Dec 22; carbon 1 p; copy 1 p; WCM letter; on publication WCM social history of economics, student's class notes (Box 11)
    - 1939 Dec 20; t.l.s. 1 p; requests WCM attend faculty conference on plight of Social Science Department (Columbia) (Box 11)
  - MacKenzie, Findlay
    - 1936 Oct 12; t.l.s. 1 p; asks WCM write Preface to volume of readings "Economic Control and planning" (Box 11)
    - 1936 Oct 15; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/10 refusal (Box 11)
  - Maitland, Arthur Steel
    - Mar 22; a.l.s. 2 p; requests copy report of Butler Commission; Hausen, Day; D. S. visit plans (Box 11)
    - 1934 Apr 4; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 3/22 (Box 11)
    - 1934 Apr 18; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 4/4; visit plans (Box 11)
    - 1934 May 3; t.l.s. 1 p; visit plans (Box 11)
    - 1934 May 31; a.l.s. 2 p; requests note on business cycles; visit news; wants Kuznets monograph on capital goods; WCM note (Box 11)
  - Mallery, Otto Ted
    - 1941 Oct 13; t.l.s. 1 p; Academy of Political Science meeting Wallace; sends copy own Economic Union and Enduring Peace; own National Resources Planning Board work (Box 11)
    - 1947 Oct 14; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy own More than Conquerors, J. Winant; requests WCM review (Box 11)
    - 1947 Oct 28; t.l.s. 1 p; reply; on Conquerors; requests review (Box 11)
    - 1947 Nov 15; a.l.s. 1 p; Conquerors; query on current business cycle and Marshall plan (Box 11)
    - 1947 Dec 26; a.l.s. 1 p; requests advertising statement for Conquerors, sends quote from National Education Association Journal (encl. 1 p) (Box 11)
  - Marchisio, Ildo E.
    - 1947 Aug 14; copy 1 p; to NB; sends report on Edizioni Scientifiche Italiane (encl. 1 p) (Box 11)
  - Marshall, George
    - 1948 May 7; own contempt of Congress conviction, requests WCM aid (Box 11)
  - Martin, P.W.
    - 1)
      - 1922 May 17; a.l.s. 1 p; sends draft "Flaw in the Price System" (encl. 12 p) (Box 11)
      - 1922 May 19; carbon 2 p; WCM reply to 5/17; criticizes "Flaw" (Box 11)
      - [1922] Oct 17; a.l.s. 2 p; sends revised copy "Flaw"; underconsumptionist errors - Rodbertus, Hobson (Box 11)
      - 1922 Nov 27; carbon 2 p; criticizes "Flaw" (Box 11)
      - 1922 Dec 12; t.l.s. 2 p; sends model of own ideas (encl. 5 p) (Box 11)
    - 2)
      - 1923 Jul 5; t.l.s. 1 p; sends final revision "Flaw", sending copy to W. Foster; BCU query - wants to review; WCM notes on back (Box 11)
      - 1923 Aug 21; t.l.s. 3 p; reply; on WCM criticisms; wants to quote WCM letter on revival process (passage encl. 2 p); BCU review (Box 11)
      - 1935 Jan 24; on BASM preparation; NRB report, permanent board (Box 11)
      - 1935 Feb 15; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; sends own talk for AAAS; Cornell lecture plans (Box 11)
      - 1947 Nov 7; copy 2 p; to Mills; on establishment of international economic associations (Box 11)
  - Mathewson, Park
    - 1921 Nov 4; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM Post articles; query on NB income study (Box 11)
    - 1921 Nov 7; carbon 1 p; (on back 11/7); WCM reply to 11/4; own work; conference on unemployment and NB; cycle control; NB income study (Box 11)
  - May, George O.
    - 1936 Oct 21; carbon 1 p; WCM reply; business and major cycles; inter-cycle differences (Box 11)
    - 1937 May 11; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for copy BASM (Box 11)
    - 1948 Mar 2; t.l.s. 1 p (by secretary); dinner meeting plans day. (Box 11)
  - May, Mark A.
    - 1937 Jan 20; t.l.s. 1 p; plans of Committee on Review of Policies and Procedures of SSRC; H. Willey, L. Worth, D. Young (Box 11)
    - 1937 Jan 20; t.l.s. 1 p; to E. Snow (WCM secretary); Committee on Review plans (Box 11)
    - 1937 Feb 4; t.l.s. 1 p; Committee on Review plans, Wirth (Box 11)
    - 1937 Feb 6; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 2/4; approves plans (Box 11)
    - 1937 Jul 17; t.l.s. 1 p; Wirth’s report to Committee on Review (Box 11)
    - 1937 Aug 3; t.l.s. 1 p; Committee on Review meeting plans, Wirth report (Box 11)
  - Mayer, Joseph
    - 1948 Aug 10; t.l.s. 1 p; asks advice on textbook on history of economic thought; thanks for advice on own Social Science Principles (Box 11)
  - McClelland, George William
    - 1946 Oct 4; t.l.?. 1 p; on University of Pennsylvania Industrial Research Department address by WCM, Balderston, Davis (Box 11)
  - McCloskey, Joseph F.
    - 1947 Dec 16; returns duplicate payment (University of Pennsylvania Press) (Box 11)
  - McCrea, Roswell C.
    - 1956 Dec 30; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; personal news, Biloxi trip (Box 11)
    - 1957 Jan 2; a.l.s. 1 p; reply to 12/50/36 personal news (Box 11)
    - 1957 Feb 6; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; personal news and comments (Box 11)
    - 1937 May 24; t.l.s. 1 p; personal news and comments (Box 11)
    - 1937 May 25; carbon 1 p; WCL4 reply to 5/24 (Box 11)
    - 1957 Nov 19; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 11/4; on financial aid to Columbia's economics students, NB (Box 11)
  - McCune, Evelyn B.
    - 1948 t.l.s. 1 p; requests WCM letter to C. Hahn; WCM note on reply (Korean Cultural -Relations Association) (Box 11)
  - McKinley, Charles
    - 1936 Aug 16; t.l.s. 1 p; wants WCM opinion on National Resources Council for own report to President's Committee on Administrative Management (Box 11)
    - 1956 Aug 51; carbon 1 p; reply to 8/16; meeting plans (Box 11)
    - 1956 Sep 14; t.l.s. 1 p: meeting plans (Box 11)
    - 1936 Oct 7; t.l.s. 1 p; meeting plans (Box 11)
    - [1956 October?]; a.l.s. [telegram draft?]; meeting plans (Box 11)
  - McLaughlin, Donald H.
    - 1947 Jan 9: t.l.s. 1 p.; sends copy own paper (not encl.) (Box 11)
  - McNiece, Thomas M.
    - 1955 Aug 30; a.d.s.. 2 p; note at end of copy "Significance of Replacement Cycles Demand"; also present "Consumer's Rate of Replacement - a Study of Demand" (8 p.) (Box 11)
  - Mead, E.S.
    - 1958 Mar 31; t.l.s. 1 p: sends copy study by Corporation Finance seminar "Common Stocks as Investments" (encl 3 p.) (Box 11)
  - Meeker, Royal
    - 1)
      - 1921 Jun 17; t.l.s. 1 p; Lusk Committee and New School; planned WCM article; HP (International Labor Office) (Box 11)
      - 1921 Dec 3; t.l.s. 1 p; renews request for WCM article (Box 11)
      - 1921 Dec 3; t.l.s. 1 p: wants BC (13); Income in the United States (Box 11)
      - 1921 December15 carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 12/3; on proposed article (Box 11)
      - 1921 Dec 15; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 12/3; on requested books (Box 11)
    - 2)
      - 1922 Feb 3; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for requested volumes (Box 11)
      - 1922 Mar 2; carbon 2 p: WC11 letter; International Labor Office practices - Meeker interest in. U.S. job; NB operation - Van Kleek, Harrison, Parmelee, Mallery, T. Adams; International Labor Review (Box 11)
      - 1922 Mar 23; t.l.s. 1 p; on NB, International Labor Review (Box 11)
      - 1922 May 30; t.l.s. 1 p; sends ILO Reconstruction Series for criticism (Box 11)
      - 1922 Jun 19; carbon 2 p; WCM reply to 5/30; Reconstruction Series; on proposed article - Souls on real income; BCU plans. (Box 11)
      - 1922 Jul 6: t.l.s. 1 p; reply 6/19; WCM article; own Europe trip (Box 11)
    - 3)
      - 1922 Sep 25; t.l.s. 2 p; WCM. return to Columbia; proposed article; wants coal and railroad strike articles: Lauck and Hanna (Box 11)
      - 1922 Oct 13; carbon 3 p; WCV. reply to 9/25; Wolman and coal strike article; New School - reorganization, WCM return to Columbia; NB work; Willis and Stewart - Federal deserve Board research; Brookings Institute - Moulton. Page (Box 11)
      - 1922 Oct 14; t.l.s. 2 p; query on Edie's Stabilization of Business: BCU query: unemployment insurance - wants article (Box 11)
      - 1922 Nov 2;t.l.s. 2 p; reply to 10/13 Wolman and strike article; New School; BCU and ILO (Box 11)
      - 1922 Nov 9; carbon 2 p; WCM reply to 10/14 Wolman and NB; National Industrial Conference Board study of unemployment insurance; Willits and strike article; Stabilization; BCU; H. Chandler end ILO publications possible suspension (Box 11)
      - 1922 Nov 20; t.l.s. 2 p; M. Thomas and Meeker - trip plans; Seager (Box 11)
      - 1922 Nov 29; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 11/9; sends Fourth International Labor Conference resolution on unemployment, H. Chandler (Box 11)
  - Melish, William Howard
    - 1945 Dec 17; see Woltman 10/23/46 (Box 11)
    - 1946 Nov 15; mimeograph 2p.: defends National Council of Soviet-American friendship: requests statement; reply-envelope encl. (Box 11)
    - 1946 Nov 15: same as above to LSM: reply envelope encl. (Box 11)
  - Merriam, Charles E.
    - 1937 March 1; t.l.s. 1 p: R. Hutchins and Academy of Political Science dinner; NRC plans (Box 11)
    - 1937 Mar 5; carbon 1 p: WCM reply to 3/1; on proposed National Economic Council - A. Adelman. Senator Bulkley (Box 11)
    - 1937 Mar 9; t.l.s. 1 p: reply to 3/5; National Economic Council-Delano, Bulkley; NRC – Ruml, Means (Box 11)
    - 1937 Oct 22; t.l.s. 1 p: copy 1 p; publication of Cornell lectures: WCM resignation from NRC (Box 11)
    - 1937 Oct 29; carbon 1 p: copy 1 p; WCM reply to 10/22 Cornell lectures: NRC; own work - essays and :NB (Box 11)
  - Merriam, John C.
    - 1937 Apr 6; t.l.s. 1 p; climatic cycles - A. Douglass, Spoehr; invites WCM to Carnegie Institution of Washington conference on climatic cycles (Box 11)
    - 1937 Apr 8; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 4/6; refusal of invitation (Box 11)
  - Merrill, Harold
    - 1939 Jul 20; mimeograph 1 p; sends "Who's Who in the National Resources Committee in 1939" (encl. 34 p); requests biographical data (Box 11)
  - Miller, Adolph C.
    - 1)
      - 1908 Nov 2; carbon 2 p; WCM letter; on University of Chicago & Univ. of Calif, appointment offer (Box 11)
      - 1908 Nov 10; a.l.s. 3 p; reply to 11/10 Chicago offer (Box 11)
      - 1908 Nov 19; telegram, reply; acknowledges WCM decision (Box 11)
      - 1908 Dec 17; a.l.s 2p}. meeting plans (Box 11)
      - 1909 Apr 30; a.l.s. 2 p; California Economics Department plans (Box 11)
    - 2)
      - 1910 May 20; a.l.s. 2 p; Department matters; personal news; praises "Rationality of Economic Activity" (Box 11)
      - 1923 Feb 9; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy own address and Federal Reserve Board conference proceedings - J. Williams (not end.); criticizes BCU (Box 11)
      - 1923 Feb 16; carbon 1 p; (on back 2/9), WCM reply to 2/9; J. Williams and Miller; ECU and own contribution (Box 11)
      - 1924 May 2; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; on Miller1s Federal Reserve Board reappointment (Box 11)
      - 1924 Jun 4; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 5/2 (Box 11)
  - Millikan, Max, Jr.
    - 1937 June 10; t.l.s. 2 p; wants meet WCM, sends Gay letter (1/30/37) (Box 11)
  - Millis, H. A.
    - 1)
      - 1933 Dec 12; t.l.s. 1 p; requests WCM do article on Laughlin (Box 11)
      - 1933 Dec 15; carbon 1 p; (on back 12/12), WCM reply to 12/12 agrees (Box 11)
      - 1934 Jan 11; t.l.s. 1 p; sends Nef note for comment (not encl.) (Box 11)
      - 1934 Jan 13; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 1/11; Nef note, Laughlin NB work (Box 11)
      - 1934 Jan 17; t.l.s. 1 p; wants WCM aid in planning AEA roundtables (Box 11)
      - 1934 Jan 25; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 1/13; sends Laughlin bibliography (Box 11)
    - 2)
      - 1934 Apr 6; carbon 1 p; copy of WCM letter; Laughlin article difficulties; WCM on Laughlin (Box 11)
      - 1934 Apr 10; t.l.s. 1 p; copy 1 p; reply to 4/6; Laughlin article, Knight (Box 11)
      - 1934 Apr 21; carbon 1 p; copy 1 p; (on back 4/10), WCM reply to 4/10? will not do Laughlin article (Box 11)
      - 1934 Apr 25; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 4/21; acknowledgement; Lehman WCM letter (Box 11)
      - 1934 Dec 13; t.l.s. 1 p; birthday dinner message (Box 11)
      - 1936 Dec 14; t.l.s. 1 p; on AKA meeting - WCM attendance; meeting plans (Box 11)
  - Mills, Frederick C.
    - 1)
      - 1936 Jun 14; t.l.s. 1 p; own Prices in Recession and Recovery progress, WCM criticisms (Box 11)
      - 1936 Jul 1; see A. Shaw (Box 11)
      - 1936 Jul 14; t.l.s. 1 p; on Friedrich letter - econometric charts; Riefler, Crum, Soule, WCM and May on Prices (Box 11)
      - 1936 Dec 2; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; thanks for copy "Price Data and problems of Price Research", query on transport series (Box 11)
      - [1936]; t.l.s. 2 p; ASA round tables, Conference on Price research; sends own "Industrial Productivity and Prices" (encl. 27 p) (Box 11)
    - 2)
      - 1937 Apr 30; t.l.s. 1 p; copy 1 p; praises BASM (Box 11)
      - 1937 Jul 31; t.l.s. 1 p; on NB Bulletin, Kuznets summary; Wickens manuscript; capital formation chart encl. ( 1 p) [Altschul-Strauss ms] (Box 11)
      - 1937 Aug 24; see S. Kuznets (Box 11)
      - 1937 Aug 26; carbon 1 p; to S. Kuznets; NB Bulletin and Kuznets’ income study summary (Box 11)
      - 1937 Aug 27; t.l.s. 2 p; Altschul and Strauss study - Riefler and Hamilton, Miss Anderson; sends copy letter to Kuznets (8/26) (Box 11)
      - 1937 Oct 21; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; Friedrich's econometric charts, Kuznets (Box 11)
    - 3)
      - 1939 Jul 6; t.l.s. 3 p; Wickens manuscript - Shaw, Kuznets, Miss Anderson, Stratton, de Chazeau, Dean, Carson; Falk Foundation - grant - Solomon; price series reorganization - Uhrbrock, Remey; Income Conference [Price Conference] (Box 11)
      - 1947 Sep 30; t.l.s. 1 p; California group lunch plans (Box 11)
      - 1947 Oct 7; California group luncheons and WCM health, C. Torey (Box 11)
      - 1947 November7; see P. Martin (Box 11)
    - 4
      - 1948 Feb 13; t.l.s. 2 p; reference cycle amplitudes of output and price; Harrod and simultaneous price and output movements (Box 11)
      - 1948 Feb 24; t.l.s. 1 p; California group luncheon plans (Box 11)
      - 1948 Mar 22; t.l.s. 1 p; prospective Hoover Commission job for NB (Box 11)
      - 1948 Apr 29; t.l.s. 1 p; NB study for Hoover Commission, wants recommendations; C. Long. (Box 11)
      - 1948 Sep 2; see W. R. Burgess (Box 11)
      - 1948 Sep 10; t.l.s. 1 p; California group lunch plans (Box 11)
  - Mitchell, W.C.
    - 1911 Oct 18; copy 10 p; WCM letter; autobiographical letter (incomplete) (Box 11)
  - Mitchell, W. T.
    - [1948 Mar ?]; see W. Donovan (Box 11)
  - Mitchell, William H.
    - 1948 May 25; t.l.s. 1 p; requests opinion on A. Achinstein for publishers (Thomas Y. Crowell) (Box 11)
    - 1948 Jun 7; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 5/30; acknowledgement of WCM statement (Box 11)
  - Moe, Henry Allen
    - 1947 Nov 12; t.l.s. 1 p; requests opinion on Guggenheim Foundation, applicant (Box 11)
  - Mohr, Otto L.
    - 1927 Mar 12; carbon 2 p; to Huxley; on World Population Conference (Geneva) on birth control (Box 11)
  - Molodovsky, Nicholas
    - 1937 May 17; see C. Shoup (Box 11)
  - Moore, Geoffrey H.
    - 1947 Jun 24; t.l.s. 1 p; ? WHDBC progress, sends conformity indexes (not end.), Forman and charts (Box 11)
    - 1947 Jul 11; t.l.s. 1 p; sends charts with revisions (not encl.); on WHDBC - A. Lowe, S. Fabricant, R. Marck (Box 11)
    - 1947 Jul 15; t.l.s. 1 p; sends money-flow table and charts by Copeland (not encl.) and comments on WHDBC (not encl.); on liabilities series - T. Hultgren (Box 11)
    - 1948 Jan 14; t.l.s. 1 p; WHDBC manuscript (Box 11)
    - 1948 Jul 13; t.l.s. 1 p; sends memorandum on ranking series as statistical indicators (not encl.); Hastey, Burns (Box 11)
    - 1948 Aug 3; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy Kendrick and Crum Federal Budget in the First Postwar Decade for comment (not encl.); on WCM comments on indicator rating plan (Box 11)
    - 1948 Aug 13; t.l.s. 1 p; reply; on WCM comments on Kendricks-Crum paper; exports series – Hastay (Box 11)
  - Moore, Henry L.
    - 1914 Sep 13; a.l.s. 2 p; on own Economic Cycles; praises BC; J.B. Clark (Box 11)
    - 1914 Nov 18; a.l.s. 1- p; sends Economic Cycles manuscript (Box 11)
    - 1924 May 2; a.l.s. 1 p; declines Toronto meeting invitation (Box 11)
    - 1924 Nov 7; a.l.s. 1 p; on WCM Presidential address for AEA; professional differences (Box 11)
    - 1924 Nov 13; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 11/7 (Box 11)
  - Morgan, Shepard
    - 1940 Nov 3; a.l.s. 3 p; on WCM letter to New York Herald Tribune on election campaign - state controls (Box 11)
    - 1940 Nov 4; carbon 2 p; on need for state action (Box 11)
  - Morgan, William Fellowes
    - 1947 Jan 22; see Horace Taylor (Box 11)
    - 1947 May 27; t.l.s. 1 p; requests funds for Social Unit Institute; financial statement encl. (1 p); note by W. Phillips encl (1 p) (Box 11)
  - Morganstern, Oskar
    - 1936 May 25; t.l.s. 2 p; invitation to conference of institutes of business cycle research; Dupriez, Tinbergen, Schwartz; sends proposed agenda (encl. 1 p) (Box 11)
    - 1937 Mar 24; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy own Limits of Economics; U.S. trip plans (Box 11)
    - 1937 May 21; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 3/24; on Limits; Tintner (Box 11)
    - 1946 Sep 13; carbon 4 p; to Fetter; sends time series study proposal - Fourier analysis; von Neumann; funds needs (Box 11)
    - 1946 Nov 26; t.l.s. 1 p; on WHDBC; suggests significance tests of specific cycle peak and trough dispersion; own work; sends copy letter to Fetter (9/13), Burns (Box 11)
  - Morris, Ray
    - 1948 Sep 2; see W. R. Burgess (Box 11)
  - Moulton, H. G.
    - 1914 Feb 7; t.l.s. 1 p; asks WCM speak at Western Economic Society conference on Federal Reserve Act; lists others asked (Box 11)
  - Mund, Vernon A.
    - 1946 Dec 28; t.l.s. 1 p; to J. Dorfman; wants WCM photograph (Box 11)
    - 1947 Jan 24; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for photograph (Box 11)
  - Murray, Evaristo
    - [1947 or 1948]; mimeograph 1 p; invitation to join Nonfiction Book Club; card encl. (Box 11)
  - Neil, Helen M. (Box 12)
    - 1947 Jul 16; t.l.s. 1 p; on WHDBC progress (NB) (Box 12)
  - Nelson, J.D.
    - 1948 Jun 8; t.l.s. 1 p; on General Electric adhesives (Box 12)
  - Niles, Mary Cushing
    - 1948 Apr 30; t.l.s. 1 p; requests WC2i photograph; own work; Taylor, H. Person, O. Tead, M. Cooke (Box 12)
    - 1948 Jun 24; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for photograph (Box 12)
  - Norton, John DeWitt
    - 1947 Jan 30; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy of Connecticut Commission study plan of employment stabilization in Connecticut industry (encl.3 p) (Box 12)
  - Notestein, Frank W.
    - 1948 Jan 23; see W. Wilcox (Box 12)
  - Noyes, C. Reinold
    - 1)
      - 1936 Oct 21; t.l.s. 2 p; own book and translation plans - economics of finance; criticizes Keynes; Hansen; meeting plans, asks aid (Box 12)
      - 1936 Oct 22; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/21 (Box 12)
      - 1936 Nov 2; t.l.s. 1 p; reply; sends outline of work plans; sends outline, "A Modern Economy" (end. 3 p) (Box 12)
      - 1936 Nov 4; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 11/2; on Noyes' outline (Box 12)
    - 2)
      - 1947 Jan 16; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy R. Pearl's Man the Animal (Box 12)
      - 1947 Feb 6; t.l.s. 1 p; reply; on Pearl's book, specialization; own new book, Hering, Semon, Butler (Box 12)
      - 1947 Mar 3; t.l.s. 1 p; meeting plans, own NB proposals (Box 12)
      - 1947 Jul 17; t.l.s. 1 p; on MBC (Box 12)
      - 1947 Aug 30; t.l.s. 1 p; reply; plans for own Economic Man; NB methods and approach (Box 12)
    - 3)
      - 1948 Jan 15; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM health; WHDBC plans; Economic Man progress (Box 12)
      - 1948 May 6; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM review of Economic Man (American Economic Review), Homan; L. Brown request, publisher's claims for book (Box 12)
      - 1948 Jun 14; t.l.s. 1 p; copy thanks for help on Economic Man; Woodworth, Mi 11s; memorandum on Economic Man encl. (2 p) (Box 12)
      - [1948] Jul 19; a.l.s. 3 p; Economic Man; on modern economics (Box 12)
      - 1948 Aug 9; t.l.s. 1 p; (signed by secretary) (Box 12)
      - 1948 Sep 2; see W. R. Burgess (Box 12)
      - 1948 Oct 13; carbon 1 p; LSM letter; WCM cannot write American Economic Review review of Economic Man; LSM note (Box 12)
  - Ogburn, Charlton
    - 1936 Sep 24; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM reply to 9/14; publication plans for address (Box 12)
    - 1936 Sep 14; t.l.s. l p; requests copy Harvard Tercentenary address (Box 12)
  - Ogburn, William F.
    - 1)
      - 1923 Feb 19; carbon 2 p; WCM letter; on Ogburn's Social Change, patents and business cycle, simultaneous discoveries in economics competitive pressure and change - consumer; social lag and social sciences (Box 12)
      - 1924 Jun 5; t.l.s. 1 p; suggest H. Feis for WCM paper on migration for ILO (Box 12)
      - 1924 Dec 9; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; Ogburn's paper on historical method - terminology of sociologists and psychologists (Box 12)
      - 1924 Dec 18; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 12/9; on terminology (Box 12)
      - 1931 Mar 30; carbon 1 p; WG4 letter; resigns as ASA representative on SSRC (Box 12)
      - 1931 Apr 4; t.l.s. 2 p; reply to 3/30; suggests SSRC alternate Mills; Wilson and Day; Committee on Social Trends plans self and Hunt; S. Rice and social statistics; crime statistics -Gehlke, Sutherland, Glueck, Moley; wants to send WCM draft of report on inventions (Box 12)
    - 2)
      - 1931 Apr 8; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 4/4; on alternate; Committee on Social Trends (Box 12)
      - 1931 Apr 11; t.l.s. 2 p; reply to A/Q; on WCM resignation; Committee on Social Trends; Mills and SSRC appointment (Box 12)
      - 1936 Jul 21; t.l.s. 1 p; asks WCM serve on SSRC Nominating Committee, Schlesinger, Regfield; own work for NRC (Box 12)
      - 1936 Jul 25; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 7/21; agrees to serve; own work (Box 12)
      - 1936 Jul 29; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 7/25; Nominating Committee (Box 12)
      - 1936 Nov 16; a.l.s. 2 p; German control of consumption (Box 12)
  - Olipburch [?], Herman